<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Development on Devops Mantra</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/categories/development/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Development on Devops Mantra</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 29 May 2023 00:26:41 +1000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/categories/development/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Unsung Heros of Interconnected world - APIs</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/api/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 May 2023 00:26:41 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/api/</guid>
      <description>In this series of article i would be explaining what is an API and what are the uses. How is it useful and what are the types of APIs. In other  parts of the series i would be discussing other aspects of API such as authenication and authorization, securing API, data validation, rate limiting and throttling, error handling and logging, secure storage solutions, least previlages prinicples, security testing, regular updates and patching and api documentation and education.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Installing Jupyter Notebook in virtual env</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/installing-jupyter-notebook-with-virtualenv/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 29 Apr 2023 21:22:51 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/installing-jupyter-notebook-with-virtualenv/</guid>
      <description>Jupyter Notebook is a popular choice among data scientist and data engineer developing application. There are numerous factors of why Jupyter Notebooks are preferred choice for getting up and running quickly. There are several posts why they do so. This article on real python nicely explains.
Here i would be describing how to install Jupyter Notebook in a personal laptop and getting up and running quickly. If you aren&amp;rsquo;t familiar with virtual env or venv, you can refer to this post.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
